翻译校对       Mam
日  听      HARERE
日听校对       Syura
翻译        阿里斯
时间轴       黑猫与牛奶
压制      娜夏
OP&ED       葉隠
Syura
诸神字幕组
嗣郎君
Oh, Shiro- kun...
Everyone else is already assembled.
Hurry and come to the classroom.
もうみんな揃っているから早く部室に行きなさい
Sorry, but I'm going to quit
the Classical Music Club.
楽部辞めるから
Huh? Why so suddenly?
どうしてまた急に
Your teacher thinks you have
a talent for playing the piano.
先生　君にはピアノの才能があると思っているんです
I won't say anything about this,
so keep at it.
悪いことは言わないから　続けなさい
You'll be popular with the girls
in the future if you can play the piano.
ピアノが弾ければ
将来女の子にモテモテですよ
Doing so would be too roundabout!
そんなの回りくどいんだよ
僕には時間がないんだ
I don't have any time!
The top floor of the south
school building...
南校舎の最上階
... at the end of the north hallway...
北側廊下の突き当り
"Music Room #3"
The unused music room...
楽室
This is it. This is the fabled...
ここだ　ここが噂の
- Welcome.
いらっしゃいませ
Oh, it's just a kid.
なんだがきか
And a boy, no less.
しかも男
What's wrong, little lost boy?
Did you need something from our palace?
どうした　迷い子
我が宮殿に何かご用かな
"Deep into the role of an Arabian king"
あんたがここのキング？
Y-you're this place's king?
- Am I wrong?
- Here, little lost boy.
違うの
来れ　迷い子
What did you just call me?
今　俺を何と呼んだかな
"King."
キング
オオオ　キング
Oh, "King"! Yes indeed,
I am the King of this Host Club.
そうとも　俺はこのホスト部のキングなのだ
"Happy, since he's not used
to being called that..."
I'm Takaoji Shiro,
Elementary 5th-Year, Class A!
初等部５年Ａ組鷹凰子嗣郎
I hereby petition the Host Club King
to take me on as an apprentice.
ホスト部キングに弟子入りを志願する
「小学生ホストはやんちゃ系」
My, Tamaki- kun, you have an apprentice?
"The Host Club is now open for business"
まあ　環くんにお弟子さんが？
Yes. He's still in grade school,
but I like the look in his eye.
まだ初等部の子だが　いい目をしていてね
Can such a small boy serve as a host?
そんな小さな子供にホストが務まりますの
Love has nothing to do with age.
恋に年齢は関係ありませんよ
いや　正直に告白すれば
No, to tell the truth,
even my heart begins to pound,
僕だって君を前にすると胸が高鳴り
and I always become like a little boy,
when you are before me.
いつだって幼い子供のようになってしまうのです
Ah, Tamaki- kun...
環君
あんな近くで見学させて
Letting him observe them
at such a close distance
has to make it difficult, doesn't it?
やりづらくないんですかね
He usually insists that he becomes
proportionally more beautiful
人は見られる距離に比例して
より美しくなると普段から力説しているからな
the closer people see him.
Let's just let them be.
まあ　放っておこう
You bad girl, who showed
me the forbidden fruit,
禁断の実を僕に教えたいけない人
you're like a mermaid princess,
bringing light to my sea of loneliness.
君は孤独という名の海に光をもたらしてくれた
人魚姫だ
I'm a mermaid princess?
私が人魚姫
If you ask me, you're more like
the carp we have in our pond at home.
どっちかっつうとうちの池のフナだよ
I wouldn't want to offer you
any such clumsy flattery.
僕はそんな見え透いたお世辞は言いたくない
Carp?
Oh, no, he's just a child, you know.
I mean, children are so frank.
いや　子供の言うことだから
ほら　子供は素直で
Frank?
素直って
S-still, they may be frank, but
I wouldn't say that you look like a carp.
でも　素直といっても
別に君がフナというわけでは
And even supposing that
you did look like a carp,
仮にフナだとしてもそれは美しい
- it's a beautiful carp...
- So I'm a carp, after all!
やっぱりフナ
No... I didn't mean...
いや　そうじゃなくて
- Tamaki- kun, you idiot!
- Wait, my mermaid princess!
環くんのバカ
待ってくれ　人魚姫
Don't cry, you crybaby.
泣き虫なフナ
Good for you, sir!
良かったじゃん殿　かわいい弟ができてさ
That's an adorable little
apprentice you have there.
Hikaru... Hikaru, do you wish
you had a brother like this?
光　光はこういう弟のほうがよかった
Silly... I could search the whole world,
バカ　世界中探したって
and not find a better brother
than you, Kaoru.
馨以上の弟なんているかよ
Oh, Hikaru...
光
Forbidden brotherly love!
禁断の兄弟愛よ
Y-you're homos! And what's worse,
you're twins, so that's kinkan youkan!
(Kinkan youkan: "kumquat bean paste")
ホモだ　しかも双子でキンカンヨウカンってやつなんだ
I think what you mean
to say is kinshin soukan.
(Kinshin soukan: "incest")
それを言うなら近親相姦なの
Shiro-chan!
嗣郎ちゃん　一緒にケーキ食べる
Want to have some cake with me?
You know what?
We have chocolate and strawberry.
あのね　チョコといちごのがあってね
Back off!
邪魔　お前何年だよ
What grade are you in!?
"Truthfully is a high school 3rd-Year"
What are you doing,
wearing a high school uniform?
なんで高等部の制服着てんの
What's wrong, Mitsukuni?
どうした　光邦
No fair! You can't go having
older friends like that!
ずるいぞ　こんな年上の仲間がいるなんて
"Truthfully in the same class"
What's the matter?
どうしたの
Ah, you're surprised at how
everyone here is so unusual?
変わった人ばかりいて驚きました
I was also unable to get a grasp
of the atmosphere around here at first,
自分も最初はここの空気が理解できず　随分と戸惑ったものです
which considerably threw me for a loop.
This one seems more like a girl.
この人　女みたい
Are you a queer?
オカマですか
Huh?
Okay, that will do.
Why don't you carry the tea for me?
ここはいいから　お茶でも運んできてくれるかな
Haruhi really is manly, isn't he?
ハルヒは本当に男らしいなあ
さあ　男らしいハルヒ君　そのティーセットは嗣郎に任せて
Go on, manly Haruhi- kun,
let Shiro take care of that tea set.
It's part of his training.
これも修行だ
"The committee to assert
that Haruhi is definitely a boy"
This kid is surprisingly sharp.
このガキ意外に鋭い
A formidable eye, for a child.
侮りがたし子供の目
Okay, it's heavy, so be careful.
じゃあ　重いから気をつけてね
It's not my fault, okay?
僕のせいじゃないからな
It's your fault for trying
to make me do it.
こんなことさせようとするお前が悪いんだ
Haruhi, -100,000 yen.
ハルヒ　マイナス１０万
Hey, you should make the queer
handle doing the chores!
雑用なんかオカマにやらしときゃいいだろう
Instead, hurry up and teach
me how to make a woman happy!
それより早く僕に女の喜ばせ方教えろよ
What kind of attitude is that?
その態度は何だ
なによりハルヒに生意気な口を聞いたのは許せん
And above all, I'm not letting you
get away with smarting off to Haruhi.
- Place him in isolation!
- Yes, sir!
こやつを隔離しろ
イエッサー
What is this!?
なんだよこれ　なんで鉄格子なんか降りてくるんだ
How come I've got cell bars
dropping down on me!?
Yeah, really, why?
本当　なんで
This is supposed to be
a music room, right?
楽室ですよね
Come on, let me out!
こら　出せ出せよ
Is this any way to treat
your dear apprentice!?
これがかわいい弟子にすることかよ
You stay in there until
you learn your lesson.
反省するまで入ってろ
I took you as my apprentice
because you were serious
本気でホストになりたいようだから弟子にしてやったが
about wanting to become a host,
but maybe my expectations were wrong.
見込み違いだったかな
I am serious. Seriously serious.
僕は本気だ　本気の本気だ
I want to become a host, too!
僕もホストになりたいんだ
I don't have any time! Show me how!
時間がないんだよ　教えてくれよ
あんたも女の子が好きだから
You like girls, too...
You like seeing girls with happy faces,
女の子の喜ぶ顔が好きだから　ホストやってんだろう
so that's why you're a host, right?
Please, show me how to do it!
頼むから教えてくれよ
You're a genius at it, aren't you, King!?
あんた天才なんだろう　キング
"Genius?"
Well, you may be sassy,
まあ　生意気だが　ホストを目指す志だけは本気のようだな
but your will to become a host
does at least seem to be genuine.
Moreover, you are a lot
like me in some ways.
それにどこか俺に似てる
You poor kid.
かわいそうに
Then, you'll turn me into the kind
of host that can make women happy!?
じゃあ　女を喜ばせるホストにしてくれるか
A host that is unable to make
a woman happy is no host at all.
女を喜ばせることができないホストなどホストではない
Very well. If that's how
badly you want it,
よかろう　そこまで言うのなら
think about how best to use
the material you've got to work with.
己の素材を活かすことを考えろ
素材
Material?
At Ouran Host Club,
我が桜蘭ホスト部は各自の特性を生かし
our fundamental policy is to use
our own personal characteristics
お客様のニーズに答えるのが基本方針だ
to meet the needs of our guests.
Starting with the "princely type,"
Tamaki...
王子様系の環を始め
"The princely type"
ワイルド系
"The strong, silent type"
ロリショタ系
"The boy-Lolita type"
小悪魔系
"The little-devil type"
クール系と
多彩なバリエーションを誇っていたが
"The cool type"
We pride ourselves
on our many variations.
With the addition of our honor student,
natural rookie, Haruhi...
優等生天然系ルーキーのハルヒが入り
"The natural type"
Natural type?
天然系？
...we've got just about
the perfect assortment.
ほぼ完璧な布陣となった
I'm not so sure we're going to find
a new type beyond these.
果たしてこれ以上新しいタイプが見つかるかな
His age suggests
the boy Lolita type...
年齢的にはショタ系だけど
...but that would overlap
with Honey- senpai.
ハニー先輩とかぶるしね
Am I in the way now?
僕もう邪魔
Tepid! Quite tepid!
ぬるい　ぬるいですわ
"Powerful motor"
Like I said, this is supposed
to be a music room, right?
楽室なんですよね
Gentlemen of the Host Club, to think
ホスト部の皆さんがこれほどキャラ分析にぬるいとは
that you'd be so lackluster
in your character analysis,
I am a little bit dumbfounded.
私少々呆れてしまいますわ
All right, Renge- kun,
では蓮華君　君なら彼の素材をどのように活かす
how would you work
with the material he's got?
We've already got the boy Lolita type
covered with Honey- senpai.
ショタ系はすでにハニー先輩がいらっしゃるのだぞ
This is why I say you're lackluster!
Listen up!
そこがぬるいというのです
いいですか　確かに低年齢層の少年や
While it's true that there are some girls
who feel their hearts beat faster
童顔男に説明しがたいときめきを覚えてしまう女の子を
in a way that's hard to explain
over boys of a younger age group,
or who have baby-faces,
who we call shotokon fans,
ショタコン好きと言いますが
それはかなりアバウトな分類で
it is still a fairly broad category,
whose preferences can be further split
その好みはさらにデリケートに分類されています
into even more delicate classifications.
Yes, while Haninozuka- senpai
may represent the little boy type
そう　埴之塚先輩はショタ系の中でも
of this boy Lolita category,
いわゆるロリショタ系の王道ですが
in his case, the direction
he should take...
彼の場合　その目指すべき方向は
...is the naughty-boy type,
without a doubt!
やんちゃ系で間違いないでしょう
"The naughty type"
The naughty type...
やんちゃ系
The essentials of the
naughty type include...
やんちゃ系の基本は
...always wearing shorts. Okay!
いつでも半ズボン
ＯＫ
Playing up your naughtiness...
膝や頬の傷で　ヤンチャさを演出
...with skinned knees and cheeks!
Run, like a spoiled child!
走れ　やんちゃに
Make it reckless!
ただがむしゃらに
When you get there, trip,
and make it big!
その辺で豪快に転ぶ
大丈夫　僕
はいそこですかさずセリフ
Okay, then you say
your line immediately!
It's nothing. No big deal.
別に　どうってことない
Perfect! It's perfect!
パーフェクツ　パーフェクツですわ
Outstanding.
すばらしい　完璧な指導だよ蓮華君
That was perfect coaching, Renge- kun.
Idiots... These people are idiots...
アホだ　この人達はアホだ
Never mind!
もういいよ
There's no way I'll make
her happy with this.
こんなで　あいつが喜ぶわけないだろう
Her?
あいつ
Hey, Shiro!
こら嗣郎　これからまだ応用テクニックのレッスンが
You still have your applied
technique lesson coming up!
Younger boys are just
no good for anything, huh?
やっぱりダメですわね　若い子は
After I took the trouble of coaching him,
he won't keep going.
せっかく工事してあげても続かなくて
What a selfish kid, not taking a liking
せっかくのレッスンが気に入らんとは
to the lessons he was getting.
なんてわがままなやつ
普通気に入りませんよあんなのは
Typically, no one would take
a liking to that sort of lesson.
But never mind that, aren't you
a little bit concerned about him?
それより　すこし気になりませんか
I don't have any time! Show me how!
時間がないんだよ　教えてくれよ
"I don't have any time."
What could that mean?
時間がないって　何なんでしょうね
What's more,
それに　「あいつ」って言ってましたよ
he said something about a "her."
How did we get to this point?
どうしてこういうことになるんだろう
We snuck in easily enough.
うまく潜入できたね
"Honey in elementary-school disguise"
これなら初等部の生徒に見えるから大丈夫だよね　ハルちゃん
I look like I'm in grade school
dressed like this,
so I'll be okay, Haru-chan.
You sure do.
確かに初等部の校舎に潜入するのに
I can understand you wearing
an elementary-school uniform
初等部の制服姿になるのは理解できますし
to sneak into the elementary school,
and Honey- senpai, I do think
you look good in that,
ハニー先輩似合ってると思いますが
"Haruhi in middle-school disguise"
but why do I have to dress up
in a middle-school outfit?
どうして自分が中等部の制服姿にならなきゃいけないんでしょう
では　作戦を開始する
All right, the mission is underway.
- Mission?
- What one?
作戦
何の
Judging from the situation,
状況から判断し　特殊潜入部隊を決定した
I've decided that
our special infiltration team...
君たち二人だ
...will be you two.
But what mission?
だから何の
十分目立ってるこの変装になんか意味はあるんでしょうか
We're standing out plenty.
Was there any reason for these disguises?
There is a reason.
There's a damn good reason.
意味はある　めちゃくちゃ意味はあるぞ
Haru-chan, that way!
ハルちゃんあっち
How cute...
なんってかわいいんだ
Ah, in that miniskirt,
she almost looks like a doll.
ミニスカート姿がまるでお人魚さんだ
In other words, you just
wanted to see her like that.
要するにお前が見たかっただけなんだな
In here. This is Shiro-chan's classroom.
ここだよ　嗣郎ちゃんの教室
When I was in elementary school,
this was my classroom, too.
僕も初等部の時　この教室だったんだ
There's nobody here.
誰もいませんね
何だ　だれもいないではないか
Oh, there's no one here, is there?
This takes me back.
懐かしいな
I wonder if my graffiti is still here.
俺の落書き残ってるかな
The school changes out
all the desks each year.
うちの学校の机は毎年総入れ替えだ
Let's go to the cafeteria after this.
あとで食堂いってみようよ
And the gymnasium, too.
あと体育館もね
Good idea, good idea.
いいねいいね
If you're going to come
in such large numbers,
そんなに大勢できたら　変装して潜入した意味ないじゃないですか
there's no reason to disguise
ourselves and sneak in, is there?
Who cares?
いいじゃん
There's nobody here.
誰もいないし
If the teacher finds us...
先生に見つかると
...it sure will be a pain coming up
with an excuse why we snuck in.
さすがに忍び込んだ言い訳が面倒だな
Shh! Be quiet!
静かに
Zip your lips!
お口にチャック
"Zip it!"
How terribly cute she is!
何じゃ　そのかわいらしさは
Looks like he's gone.
行ったみたいです
But now that we've snuck in like this,
でもこうして潜入してみてもどうやって嗣郎君のことを探るんです
how are we going to find out
more about Shiro- kun?
Here's something interesting.
面白い物があるよ
What is it?
何ですか
Shiro- kun?
嗣郎君
The Classical Music Club, huh?
楽部か
He seems to be enjoying himself.
なんか楽しそう
So Shiro- kun really can look
like that, when he smiles.
本当はこんな顔で笑うんですね　嗣郎君って
"Elementary Music Room"
Yeah.
There he is. That's Shiro- chan.
いた　嗣郎ちゃんだ
Takaoji- kun...
鷹凰子君
Did you practice the new piano piece?
ピアノの新しいところ　練習してきた
No, not that much.
いや　余し
Well then, I'll show you.
Come play it with me.
それじゃ　教えてあげるから一緒に弾こう
Nah, that's okay.
いいよ　別に
There's only one grand piano.
グランドピアノ一つなんだし　神城が使えばいいじゃん
You should use it, Kamishiro.
Okay, I will.
分かった　じゃ弾きたくなったら言ってね
But if you want to play,
too, just say so.
Pardon me, miss...
もし　そこのお嬢さん
君より美しいバラは見つからなかったけれど
I could not find a rose
more beautiful than you,
but please, take this.
どうぞこれを
Incidentally, I wonder
if you would tell me about
どころで　あそこでピアノを弾いている彼女のことを
that girl playing the piano.
教えて欲しいんだけど
神城雛ちゃん
Kamishiro Hina-chan?
Hina-chan, is it?
雛ちゃんか
You better not go falling
in love with Hina-chan.
ダメよ　雛ちゃんのこと好きになっても
You know what?
あのね　雛ちゃんもうじき引っ越しちゃうの
Hina-chan is going
to be moving away real soon.
Her father has to move to Germany
お父さんのお仕事の都合でね
for his job before the end of next week.
来週いっぱいでドイツに行っちゃうのよ
What are you doing!?
何してんだよ
What are you doing here!?
こんなところで何してんだよ
こら　何すんだよ
Hey! What are you doing!?
Put me down! Put me down!
降ろせ　降ろせよ
Stop thrashing around.
Guys, we're leaving.
暴れるな
離せって
みんな撤収だ
Put me down!
降ろせ
What do you think you're doing,
you idiot king!?
何のつもりだ　バカキング
バカはお前だ
You're the idiot.
Teach you how to make
women happy, you say?
女を喜ばせる方法を教えろだ
Don't make me laugh!
笑わせんな
However much you ask,
how are we to answer that?
いくら俺たちに聞いたって答えられるか
It's not some unspecified number
of girls you want to make happy,
お前が喜ばせたいのは不特定多数の女の子じゃなくて
it's just one girl,
Kamishiro Hina, isn't it?
あの神城雛　たった一人なんだろうが
Only you can find the way
to do that, right?
そんな方法　お前にしか見つけられるわけないだろう
Listen to me, as hosts,
it's our job to make the girls happy.
いいか　俺たちホストは女の子たちを喜ばせるのが仕事だ
But the truth is, when it comes
to a single girl that you like,
だが本当に個人的に好きな女の子にはホストとしてではなく
it's not as a host that
you must face her, but as a man.
一人の男として向き合うしかない
It's not being a full-fledged host
that you want to become,
お前が目指すのは　一人前のホストじゃなくて
it's a full-fledged man, isn't it?
一人前の男だろう
It doesn't matter anymore.
There's no time.
いいよ　もう　時間ないし
I just wanted to at least watch her play
せめてあいつが弾いてるとこ　できるだけ見ときたいんだ
as much as I could before she left.
That's all.
だから…
That set piece was a duet arrangement
of a Mozart sonata, right?
今の課題曲　モーツァルトソナタ連弾用か
Has there always been
a grand piano in this room?
この部屋　グランドピアノなんてありましたっけ
This is supposed to be
a music room, after all.
楽室だから
Yes, even though it may not be in use.
そう　使ってないとはいえね
It is a music room, after all.
音楽室だからな
Music room.
音楽室だ
It was there before, it was just
where you couldn't see it.
見えないところに前からあったんだよ
Awesome...
Takaoji- kun, you're always listening
to me play the piano, huh?
鷹凰子君　いつも私のピアノ聞いてるよね
Do you like the piano?
ピアノ好きなの
なら　一緒に習おうよ
If so, let's learn it together.
It really wasn't the piano that I liked.
本当に好きだったのはピアノじゃなかった
For the next week, your early
mornings, lunch recesses,
これから一週間の早朝　昼休み　放課後
and after-school periods will be spent
in concentrated piano training.
ピアノの集中大特訓だ
Get yourself ready.
覚悟しろよ
W-why?
なんで
You did become my apprentice, right?
お前は俺に弟子入りしたんだろう
Besides, that girl looked like...
それに俺にはあの子が
...she wanted to play together with you.
お前と一緒に弾きたがってたようにみえたぞ
"Music Room #3"
"You are invited
September 3rd at 3pm
to a private recital."
いらっしゃいませ　お姫様
- Welcome, princess.
Today's main program
will be Takaoji Shiro's...
本日のメイン　鷹凰子嗣郎の
...piano recital.
ピアノでございます
Princess, if you please.
お姫様　さあどうぞ
一緒に弾こうよ
Let's play together.
Mm-hmm!
We've done a good thing.
いいことをした
Wholehearted love...
一途な恋か
Is that another way that Shiro- kun
takes after you, Tamaki- senpai?
そんなところも嗣郎君は環先輩に似てるんですか
Yeah, positively so.
そっくりだ
"10 days later"
So, you're exchanging emails
with Hina-chan in Germany every day?
それじゃ　ドイツに行った雛ちゃんとは毎日メール交換を
More or less.
まあね　けどあいつ　意外とヤキモチやきなんだよな
But she's a lot more jealous
than you'd expect.
だからこんな綺麗なお姉さんたちと仲良くしてるなんて
So let's keep the fact that
I'm getting along so well
with you pretty ladies a secret, okay?
秘密な
- Oh, how cute!
- Pretty ladies, he says!
かわいい
綺麗なお姉さんですって
弟にしたい
- I wish he was my little brother.
- Naughty boys are the best!
やんちゃ系
- I could just kiss you.
- Me too.
もうチューしちゃう
私も
W-why does he have
to take my guests, too?
何故に　俺の客まで
It's easy to be popular
with the women.
女にモテんのなんて簡単だね
You had your guests taken
from you so easily,
あっさり客取られて
are you sure you can call
yourself the Host King?
あんた本当にそれでもホストキング
I thought he came off looking
pretty good for a change...
たまに格好良く決めたと思ったけど
...but it ended up with this
for a payoff after all.
所詮はこういう落ちだったか
He really is just like Tamaki- senpai.
確かに環先輩とそっくりだ
離せ
I'm sure that Senpai must have been
like that when he was a child, too.
きっと先輩も子供の頃からああだったんでしょうね
I was not! I absolutely was not,
Haruhi! I was... I was...
違う　それは断じて違うぞハルヒ
俺は　俺はな　ちょっぴりおませなイノセントボイだったのだぞ
...just a little precocious,
innocent boy!
All right, we're at the pool next!
やったあ　次はプールだ
We'll be able to see
Haruhi in a swimsuit!
ハルヒの水着が見られるぞ
Oh, no! Honey- senpai is being
taken away by a swift current!
大変だ　ハニー先輩が激流に流されて
Next time, "Jungle Pool SOS"
Ouran High School Host Club
will be waiting for you, next week!
桜蘭高校ホストクラブ　来週も
お待ちしております